This is a readme file of the Crop Usage v 1.0 database
Crop Usage v 1.0 was curated by Elizabeth Drake, Alice Graham, Bethany Hanson, Georgia Leigh, Daniel Plant, Hannah Tingle, Steven Verheul and Lucy Williamson, and is deposited in GitHub: https://github.com/Crop-Antiquity-Project/Crop_Usage_v.1.0
This database includes a list of crop species cultivated for food, and data on antiquity of cultivation; biogeography; area under cultivation; whether a crop is considered major or minor, and categorical and count data on crop usage. 
Data on the antiquity of cultivation for each crop species, as well as the biogeographic region of origin of each crop's wild progenitor, were sourced from the live version of Crop Origins database (https://github.com/rubenmilla/Crop_Origins_Phylo), accessed on the 08/02/2021. 
Data on the yearly production (hectares) averaged for the period 2006-2016 were obtained from Milla and Osborne (2021), based on data available from FAOSTAT. 
The database is comprised of three files:
The current readme file; 
a file with literature sources used to get data on crop usage (Sources Crop Usage v 1.0.txt);
the database itself (Crop Usage v 1.0.csv).

Key of column headers

Common_name      common name of crop species
Species_name      crop taxon binomial 
Minimum_time_cultivation      earliest evidence of exploitation under cultivation (y.a.)         
Primary_use (Historic)      original primary use of crop species
Secondary_use      secondary use of crop species
Current_use      current primary use of crop species
No_Food_Uses      number of food uses found for crop species
No_Non_Food_Uses      number of non-food uses found for crop species
No_Total_Uses      total number of uses found for each crop
Multi-uses_codes      the uses found for each crop species
Biogeographic_Region      the ecoregion of each crops wild progenitor
Major(1)/Minor(0)      whether a crop is considered major (1) or minor (0) - crops included in FAOSTAT data are considered major and all others are considered minor
Area_Grown_(ha)      the total area of cultivation for each crop in hectares
Sources_additional_uses      literature other than the standard sources used to get data on crop usage
Access_Date      the date sources were accessed for each crop



